<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<article desc="configuration">
   <meta desc="This article presents the configuration of the application" />
   The Options =&gt; Settings action allows to edit the configuration of the tool.

   The configuration of the tool has two types of settings:
   <ul>
      <li>The General settings</li>
      <li>The Schemas settings</li>
      <li>The SPARQL settings</li>
      <li>The Scripts settings</li>
      <li>The Styles settings</li>
      <li>The Packages settings</li>
      <li>The yEd settings</li>
   </ul>

   <title title="General settings" />
   <img id="configGeneral" />
   <ul>
      <li>"Auto Refresh": checked if the <ref id="Dependencies window" /> is refreshed when selecting an element</li>
      <li>"Include Individuals": checked if individuals must be included in the result</li>
      <li>"Show Relation Constraints": checked if cardinality constraints must be presented on data objects relations</li>
      <li>"Show DataProperties types": checked if the types of DataProperties must be presented</li>
      <li>"Show Indirect Relations": checked if the indirect relations are shown in the <ref id="Dependencies window" /></li>
      <li>"Show Alias": checked if the link between Alias Classes should be shown in the diagrams</li>
      <li>"Show Commented Elements": checked if elements which have comments must be shown with a specific icon. See also
         <ref id="elements default annotations" /> for more information</li>
      <li>"Include Parent Relations in Dependencies": checked if the Superclass relations must be shown in the Dependencies window for a Class</li>
      <li>"Include Alias Relations in Dependencies": checked if the Alias relations must be shown in the Dependencies window for a Class</li>
      <li>"Add Thing Class": checked if the <code>Thing</code> class should be present</li>
      <li>"Strict Mode": set if the browser is currently in strict checking mode. Strict mode means that converting a common resource to a
         particular language element, such as an ontology class, will be subject to some simple syntactic-level checks for appropriateness</li>
      <li>"Model Specification": set the ontology model specification used to construct the Ontology model. See also <ref id="Model Specification" /> for
         more information</li>
      <li>"Log Level": specifies the Log level which will be shown in the console</li>
   </ul>

   <title title="Schemas settings" />
   <moreInfo id="Schemas alternate locations" />
   <img id="configSchemas" />
   <ul>
      <li>"Schemas Repository": the repository of Schemas used for the graph of imported ontologies. See also <ref id="Imported Ontologies graph" />
         for more information. See also <ref id="Imported Ontologies graph" /> for more information</li>
      <li>"Use built-in Schemas": checked if the browser must use built-in schemas</li>
      <li>"Schemas Alternate Locations": allow to specify alternate locations for URIs imported in your Ontologies. See also
         <ref id="Schemas alternate locations" /> for more information</li>
   </ul>

   <title title="SPARQL settings" />
   <moreInfo id="SPARQL execution" />
   <img id="configSPARQL" />
   <ul>
      <li>"Add Prefix in SPARQL Requests": checked if the prefixes for the current schema must be automatically included in the SPARQL requests</li>
      <li>"Default Base Prefix": the default base prefix to use in the automatically included prefix  if the base prefix of the schema is empty</li>
   </ul>

   <title title="Scripts settings" />
   <moreInfo id="Scripts execution" />
   <img id="configScripts" />
   <ul>
      <li>"End Script at First Exception": checked if the script is aborted at the first exception</li>
   </ul>

   <title title="Styles settings" />
   <moreInfo id="custom styles" />
   <img id="configStyles" />
   <ul>
      <li>"Width Padding" : the padding for the boxes widths</li>
      <li>"Height Padding" : the padding for the boxes height</li>
      <li>"Has Custom Styles": checked if the style of diagrams is customized</li>
      <li>"Custom Styles": the file specifying the custom style of diagrams</li>
   </ul>

   <title title="Packages settings" />
   <moreInfo id="packages" />
   <img id="configPackages" />
   <ul>
      <li>"Show Packages": show <ref id="Packages" /> when opening an OWL/RDF diagram</li>
      <li>"Show Packages as Closed": show Packages as closed when opening an OWL/RDF diagram</li>
      <li>"Show Packages in Packages View": show Packages in Packages View when opening an OWL/RDF diagram</li>
      <li>"Has Packages Configuration": checked if there is a customized Packages configuration</li>
      <li>"Packages Configuration": the file specifying the customized Packages configuration, see <ref id="Packages Configuration" /></li>
   </ul>

   <title title="yEd settings" keepCase="true" />
   <img id="configYed" />
   <ul>
      <li>"Has yEd exe directory": checked to set the directory of the <ref id="yEd" /> graph tool</li>
      <li>"yEd exe directory": the directory of the <ref id="yEd" /> graph tool</li>
   </ul>

   <cat id="configuration" />
</article>
