<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<article desc="diagrams content">
   <meta desc="This article presents the diagrams content" />
   The <ref id="yEd" /> diagrams <ref id="Exporting diagrams" desc="exported" /> by the tool show the structure of the OWL/RDF ontology. They present:
   <ul>
      <li>The Classes</li>
      <li>The Object properties</li>
      <li>The Data properties</li>
      <li>The Individuals</li>
      <li>The <ref id="packages" /></li>
   </ul>

   <messageBox type="warning">
      Note that there are several kind of exports showing different elements. See  <ref id="Exporting diagrams" /> for more information.
   </messageBox>

   <messageBox type="info">
      All the colors which are presented here are the default colors. it is possible to customize the colors (see <ref id="custom styles" /> for more information.
   </messageBox>

   <title title="Classes" />
   Classes are presented in a grey background:
   <img id="diagramclass"/>

   Sub-classes are presented with an inheritance UML sign:
   <img id="diagramsuperclass"/>

   <title title="Object properties" />
   The relationships between Classes through Object properties is represented by an arrow from the Domain to the Range:
   <ul>
      <li>The text alongside the arrow is the name of the Object property</li>
      <li>If the "Show Relation Constraints" configuration property is selected, the cardinality is also presented near the Range Class if it is defined</li>
   </ul>
   <img id="diagramclass"/>

   <title title="Data properties" />
   A Data property is presented on a cyan blackground. The relationship between the Classes and this Data property is presented with an arrow
   by an arrow from the Class to the Data property:
   <img id="diagramdataproperty"/>

   <ul>
      <li>If the "Show Relation Constraints" configuration property is selected, the cardinality is also presented near the Data property if it is defined</li>
   </ul>

   If the "Show DataProperties types" configuration property is selected, the datatype of the Data property is also presented:
   <img id="diagramdataproperty2"/>

   <title title="Individuals" />
   An Individual is presented on a magenta background. The relationship between the Classes and this Individual is presented with an arrow
   by an arrow from the Class to the Individual:
   <img id="diagramindividual"/>

   <title title="Alias" />
   Alias Classes and Data properties are presented with a dotted line between the equivalent elements:
   <img id="diagramalias" />

   <title title="Packages" />
   <ref id="Packages" /> are group nodes which are presented on a green background:
   <img id="diagrampackages" />

   It is possible to open the content of the package to see the Classes in the package:
   <img id="diagrampackages2" />

   <see id="Exporting diagrams" />
   <see id="custom styles" />
   <see id="configuration" />
   <cat id="general" />
</article>
