<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<article desc="Diagrams export layout">
    <meta desc="This article presents the layout options for exporting diagrams in the GraphML format" />
    This article presents the layout options for exporting diagrams in the GraphML format.
   
    <title title="overview" />
    By default the <ref id="yEd" /> diagrams exported by the tool are all positioned on (0, 0), which means that all the nodes are on top of one another. For
    example:
    <img id="export2Small" />
    This means that some of the results may not be what you want:
    <ul>
        <li>The inheritance symbol for a Super-class may be presented on the top side of the Super-class</li>
        <li>Sub-classes may be presented above their super-classes</li>
        <li>The data properties of a Class may be presented above their associated Classes</li>
        <li>The Individuals of a Class may be presented above their associated Classes</li>
    </ul>
   
    However, the <ref id="configuration#Styles settings" desc="configuration" /> allows to specify the relative position of nodes in the export to improve the
    result of the diagram after applying a <ref id="yed#apply a hierarchical layout on the diagram" desc="hierarchical layout" /> in <ref id="yEd" />.
   
    <title title="options" />
    The "Layout option" option in the <ref id="configuration#Styles settings" desc="Styles settings" /> allow to configure the export to improve the
    layout of the resulting diagram after applying the <ref id="yed#apply a hierarchical layout on the diagram" desc="hierarchical layout" /> in <ref id="yEd" />.
   
    The possible states are:
    <ul>
        <li>"No Constraint": the default state, all the nodes are on (0, 0), which means that all the nodes are on top of one another</li>
        <li>"Connector on South side": Connectors for Super-Classes to their Sub-Classes are always presented at the bottom of the Super-Class. Also 
            connectors for Classes to their  data properties are always presented at the bottom of the Class</li>
        <li>"Sub-Classes on South Relative Position": Additionally, sub-classes should be presented below their super-classes</li>
        <li>"Children on South Relative Position": Additionally, Data properties and Individuals should be presented below their super-classes</li>
    </ul>
    
    <title title="example" />
    Suppose the following Ontology:
   For example, suppose the following Owl/RDF diagram:
   <img id="export1" width="60%" />

   The result of the export is the following, when opened with yEd:
   <img id="export2" width="60%" />
   
   If you apply a Hierarchical layout:
   <img id="exportHierarchicalLayout" />   

   The result will be:
   <img id="exportResultHierarchical" />    
   
   If you specify the "Children on South Relative Position", and you check the "Use Drawing As Sketch" checkbox, you will have the following result:
   <img id="exportResultHierarchical2" />

    <see id="yEd"/>
    <see id="configuration"/>
    <see id="Exporting diagrams"/>
    <cat id="browser" />
</article>
