<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<article desc="Using the yEd tool">
   <altTitle desc="yEd" keepCase="true" />
   <meta desc="This article explains how to use the yed tool on exported Owl/RDL schemas" />
   The diagrams exported by the tool use the GraphML format, compatible with the <a href="https://www.yworks.com/products/yed">yEd</a> free editor.

   <title title="overview" />
   The yEd tool is a free diagram editor allowing to show, export and manipulate diagrams in the <a href="http://graphml.graphdrawing.org/">GraphML</a> format<note>To download the
      yEd tool, go to the <a href="https://www.yworks.com/products/yed/download#download">www.yworks.com/products/yed/download</a> page</note>

   The export feature of the tool produce graphML files wich are compatible with the yEd tool.

   <messageBox type="warning">
      Note that the exported diagrams have no layout, you will need to use the layout features of yEd to obtain a readable diagram.
   </messageBox>

   <title title="layout"/>
   <title level="2" title="apply a full layout"/>
   The exported diagrams have no layout, you will need to use the layout features of yEd to obtain a readable diagram.

   For example, suppose the following Owl/RDF diagram:
   <img id="export1" width="60%" />

   The result of the export is the following, when opened with yEd:
   <img id="export2" width="60%" />

   You can apply a Tree layout:
   <img id="exportTreeLayout" />

   <messageBox type="warning">
      The Hierarchical Layout does not keep edge labels alongside the edges, which the reason why we advise to use the tree layout.
   </messageBox>

   The result will be:
   <img id="exportResult" width="60%" />

   You can apply an edge routing:
   <img id="edgerouting" />

   The result will be:
   <img id="exportResult" width="60%" />

   <title level="2" title="apply edges routing"/>
   It is mpossible to apply edges oouting without moving the nodes, which can be useful if you moved node after applying a full layout, and you only want
   to fix the edged paths.

   For example, suppose the follwing diagram, after we moved the <code>Class3</code> node:
   <img id="diagramafternodemove" width="60%" />

   You can apply edges routing:
   <img id="edgerouting" />

   The result will be:
   <img id="diagramafternodemoveedgerouting" width="60%" />

   <title title="GraphML format"/>
   The yEd tool is compatible with the standardized GraphML format which is the graph output format of the Ontology browser tool.

   <cat id="general" />
</article>
