<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<article desc="Model window">
   <altTitle desc="content window" />
   <altTitle desc="content tree" />
   <meta desc="This article presents the content of the application Browser model window" />
   This article presents the content of the application Browser model window.
   <img id="modelwindow" width="40%" />

   After opening a diagram, a tab opens in the browser showing:
   <ul>
      <li>At the left the structure of the Owl model</li>
      <li>At the right the diagram showing the model, and a window presenting the annotations on the selected
         element on the tree</li>
   </ul>

   The structure of the Owl model is separated in six tabs:
   <ul>
      <li>The Ontology tab, showing the metadata on the Ontology, and its namespaces and imported ontologies</li>
      <li>The Annotations tab, showing the Annotations definitions</li>
      <li>The Datatypes tab, showing the Datatypes definitions</li>
      <li>The Classes tab, showing the Owl Classes</li>
      <li>The Properties tab, showing the Object properties and the Data properties</li>
      <li>The Individuals tab, showing the Individuals</li>
   </ul>
   
   <title title="Refreshing the content of the tab" />
   A right-click on the tab for the opened Owl model shows a menu with two options:
   <ul>
      <li>Reload: reload the file and refresh the content of the tree</li>
      <li>Refresh tree: refresh the content of the tree, using the current Owl model</li>
   </ul>
   <img id="refresh" />

   <title title="Ontology tab" />
   The Ontology tab shows the metadata on the Ontology, and its namespaces and imported ontologies:
   <img id="tabontology" width="20%"/>

   <title level="2" title="Ontology Menu" />
   If you right click on the root ontology element in the tree, you will have the following popup menu:
   <img id="classMenu" />
   <ul>
      <li>Show Ontology Imports graph in yEd in yEd: open the graph of imported ontologies in <ref id="yEd"/></li>
   </ul>
   For example, with the following Ontology:
   <img id="tabontology" width="20%"/>
   We will have the following diagram:
   <img id="ontologygraph" />

   <title title="Class structure tab" />
   The Class structure tab shows the structure of the Class hierarchy:
   <img id="tabclasses" />

   <title level="2" title="Class Menu" />
   If you right click on a Class on this tab, you will have the following popup menu:
   <img id="classMenu" />
   <ul>
      <li>Show Dependencies: show the <ref id="Dependencies window" desc="dependencies" /> of the Class</li>
      <li>Copy to Clipboard: copy the Class IRI to the system Clipboard</li>
      <li>Export Class: export the Class and its associated Classes / Individuals and Properties as a GraphML diagram</li>
      <li>Show Class in yEd: open the Class and its associated Classes / Individuals and Properties in <ref id="yEd"/></li>
   </ul>

   <messageBox type="info">
      If  the "Multi Selection" <ref id="configuration" /> setting is selected, it is possible to select more than one Class in the Classes tree. The
      "Export Class" an "Show Class in yEd" actions will export the content of the selected Classes and their associated Classes / Individuals and Properties.
   </messageBox>

   <title level="2" title="Package Menu" />
   If you right click on a Package on this tab, you will have the following popup menu:
   <img id="packageMenu" />
   <ul>
      <li>Show Dependencies: show the <ref id="Dependencies window" desc="dependencies" /> of the Class</li>
      <li>Copy to Clipboard: copy the Class IRI to the system Clipboard</li>
      <li>Export Package: export the Package and its associated Classes / Individuals and Properties as a GraphML diagram</li>
      <li>Show Package in yEd: open the Package and its associated Classes / Individuals and Properties in <ref id="yEd"/></li>
   </ul>

   <title title="Properties tab" />
   The Properties structure tab shows the Properties, separated in data properties and object properties:
   <img id="tabproperties" />

   <title level="2" title="Property Menu" />
   If you right click on a Property on this tab, you will have the following popup menu:
   <img id="propertyMenu" />
   <ul>
      <li>Show Dependencies: show the <ref id="Dependencies window" desc="dependencies" /> of the Property</li>
      <li>Copy to Clipboard: copy the Property IRI to the system Clipboard</li>
   </ul>

   <title title="Annotations tab" />
   The Annoations tab shows the annotations tags in the model:
   <img id="tabannotations"/>

   <title level="2" title="Individuals tab" />
   The Individuals tab shows the Individuals:
   <img id="tabindividuals" />

   <title level="2" title="Individual Menu" />
   If you right click on an Individual on this tab, you will have the following popup menu:
   <img id="individualMenu" />
   <ul>
      <li>Show Dependencies: show the <ref id="Dependencies window" desc="dependencies" /> of the Individual</li>
      <li>Copy to Clipboard: copy the Individual IRI to the system Clipboard</li>
   </ul>

   <title title="element comments" />
   If an element (a Class, a property, or an Individual) has comments or a description in the
   <a href="https://www.dublincore.org/schemas/rdfs/">Dublin Core</a> <code>terms</code> schema, then these comments will be shown as a
   tooltip on the element. For example:
   <img id="tooltips" />

   <messageBox type="info">
      By default the description will be shown in the tooltip, but if there is no description and comments, there comments will be shown instead.
   </messageBox>

   <see id="Browser" />
   <see id="diagrams content" />
   <see id="Usage" />
   <cat id="general" />
</article>
